<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | Christian Decker</title>
    <link>https://christiandecker.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://christiandecker.github.io/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://christiandecker.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://christiandecker.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in a Five Star Rating? An Empirical Model of Bayesian Persuasion</title>
      <link>https://christiandecker.github.io/jobmarketpaper/sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christiandecker.github.io/jobmarketpaper/sbp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Creating trust between strangers is the backbone of the sharing-economy business model. In this context, consumer ratings are arguably the most important source of information on trustworthiness and quality. However, we observe extremely little variation (and hence information) in star ratings on major platforms. In this paper, I study the Airbnb rating system in a Bayesian persuasion framework (Kamenica and Gentzkow, 2011) by treating ratings as signals for unobserved quality. With the design of the rating system, the platform chooses an information structure to maximize the share of customers who choose the platform over outside options and thus their commissions. This approach reveals the importance of ratings for the functioning of the platform but also Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s incentives to design a rating system that encourages imperfect information transmission on quality. I set up a numerically solvable demand model of the short-term accommodation market around this Bayesian persuasion problem and its interplay with the platform’s pricing decision and hosts’ decision to join the platform and exert costly effort to improve their quality. I exploit variation in the rating distribution and market conditions across 56 major travel destinations in the United States over the years 2018 and 2019 to structurally estimate this model and back out the distribution of unobserved quality. Counterfactual exercises suggest that (i) the platform would break down without a rating system, and (ii) Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s strategic rating system design led to a consumer welfare loss of USD288M and a redistribution of profits form high to medium quality hosts of almost USD750M compared to fully revealing ratings in the markets and period studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draft coming soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
